Do you know anyone who has gone backpacking?
你认识背包旅行过的人吗？
It's a type of travel that is low-cost and independent, often meaning no fixed plans regarding accommodation or destination.
这是一种低成本、独立的旅行方式，通常意味着没有关于住宿或目的地的固定计划。"
The word 'backpacking' comes from 'backpack', a type of bag that you carry on your back.
背包旅行"一词源于"背包"，一种背在背上的包。
Travellers typically fill a backpack with life essentials, like clothing, plus anything extra needed for adventure.
旅行者的背包里通常是生活必需品，比如衣物，以及冒险所需的任何额外物品。
The stereotypical view of a backpacker is someone in their 20s, keen to tick off items on their bucket list.
对背包客的刻板印象是二十多岁、热衷于完成人生愿望清单上事项的人。
But, forget this.
但是，别管这个了。
You're about to find out that anyone can backpack.
你即将发现，任何人都可以背包旅行。
Last year, my best friend's parents retired at aged 65 and set off on a 630-mile trail along the southwest coast of England.
去年，我最好的朋友的父母在65岁时退休，出发沿英格兰西南海岸进行了一次630英里的徒步旅行。
Each carrying a 15kg backpack, Mike and Lorraine hiked along cliffs, explored golden sandy beaches and even cycled.
迈克和洛林每人背着一个15公斤的背包，沿着悬崖徒步，探索金色的沙滩，甚至骑了自行车。
For accommodation, they didn't pre-book but stayed in whatever they could find on the day, which varied from B&Bs to camping in fields full of sheep.
至于住宿，他们没有提前预订，而是当天找到什么就住什么，从民宿到满是羊群的田野里露营，各种形式都有。
They did stop for the occasional well-deserved cup of tea – they were in England after all.
他们确实也会偶尔停下来喝杯理所应得的茶——毕竟他们是在英格兰。
Backpackers are also known for travelling with little money, but few begin with as little as Othmane Zolati from Morocco.
背包客也以花钱少旅行而闻名，但很少有人像来自摩洛哥的奥斯曼·佐拉蒂那样起步资金那么少。
In 2015, he embarked on an almost four-year journey, but he started out with just $80 (£64).
2015年，他开启了一段近四年的旅程，但出发时身上只有80美元。
He zigzagged across 24 countries on the African continent and filmed his experience, aiming to show the world the diversity and beauty of Africa, all on a shoestring budget.
他在非洲大陆上的24个国家间曲折穿行，并用镜头记录下自己的经历，旨在向世界展示非洲的多样性和美丽，而这一切都靠着极少的预算。
He told BBC What's New that he often had to work odd jobs and rely on the kindness of strangers to be able to afford to keep travelling.
他告诉BBC《新鲜事》节目，为了能继续旅行，他常常不得不打零工，并依靠陌生人的善意。
But it was worth it.
但这很值得。
South Africa was Othmane's final destination and, on reaching it, he said "It was one of the best moments in my life.
南非是奥斯曼的最终目的地，到达时，他说："那是我一生中最美好的时刻之一。
It made me know that if you fight for something, you really stick to that goal… then you will reach it".
它让我明白，如果你为某件事奋斗，就专注于那个目标……那么你就能实现它。"
So, don't give up.
所以，不要放弃。
If you want to travel, you can, no matter your age or budget!
如果你想旅行，你就可以，无论你的年龄或预算如何！